Finding Aid for John B. Swainson Papers 1943-1975
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Gubernatorial Career (1961-1963) 1960-1963
  - 1961 files
    - Boards and Commissions
      - Waterways Commission
        - Sugar Island and Celeron Island (Box 14)
        - Trenton Channel (Box 14)
      - Workmen's Compensation Department
        - General (Box 14)
        - William Hart file (Box 14)
        - Appeal Board (Box 14)
      - Workmen's Compensation Study Commission (Box 14)
    - General Subjects
      - Aging, White House Conference on (Box 14)
      - Agriculture (Box 14)
      - Appointments (Box 14)
      - Area Redevelopment
        - General (Box 14)
        - Letters (Box 14)
        - State-Federal Conference on Retraining November 6, 1961 (Box 14)
        - Federal legislation (Box 15)
        - Rural Area Redevelopment (Box 15)
      - Armed Forces Day (Box 15)
      - Atomic Energy (Box 15)
      - Automation (Box 15)
      - Boy Scouts (Box 15)
      - Cancer Crusade (Box 15)
      - Census (Box 15)
      - Certificates-Citations (Box 15)
      - Civil Rights, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Community Chest (Box 15)
      - Conferences
        - General (Box 15)
        - Mental Health and Education (Box 15)
        - Mental Health, Special Governor's Conference on (Box 15)
        - National Tax Association (Box 15)
        - Rivers and Harbors Congress (Box 15)
      - Constitutional Convention (Box 16)
      - Consulates (Box 17)
      - Consumers Advisors (Box 17)
      - Council of State Governments (Box 17)
      - Counties
        - Huron (Box 17)
        - Ingham (Box 17)
        - Osceola (Box 17)
        - Schoolcraft (Box 17)
      - Detroit, City of (Box 17)
      - Disaster relief (Box 17)
      - Distressed Areas (Box 17)
      - Food for Peace (Box 17)
      - Friend of the Court (Box 17)
      - Fulbright Scholarship (Box 17)
      - Education
        - General, 2 folders (Box 17)
        - Adult Education (Box 17)
        - Educational TV (Box 17)
        - Higher Education (Box 17)
        - Primary Education (Box 17)
        - Religious Education (Box 17)
        - Scholarships (Box 17)
      - Elections (Box 17)
      - Emergency Interim Successors (Box 17)
      - Great Lakes Economic Conference (Box 17)
      - Greater Michigan Authority (Box 17)
      - Health
        - General (Box 17)
        - Polio Program (Box 17)
      - Housing (Box 17)
      - Inauguration (Box 17)
      - Inter-Agency Council for Recreation (Box 17)
      - Judgeships
        - Appointment miscellanea (Box 17)
        - Canham, James (Box 17)
        - Deneweth, George (Box 17)
        - Montante, James (Box 17)
      - Juvenile Delinquency-federal legislation HR 7178 (Box 17)
      - Lake Michigan Region Planning Committee (Box 17)
      - Letters to Department Heads (Box 17)
      - Library cards (Box 17)
      - Local government (Box 17)
      - Migrant labor (Box 17)
      - Natural resources (Box 17)
      - Newsletters of the governor (Box 17)
      - Port developments (Box 18)
      - Press releases (Box 18)
      - Reapportionment (Box 18)
      - Recreation (Box 18)
      - Removal (Box 18)
      - Safety (Box 18)
      - Staff meetings April 11-13, 1961 (Box 18)
      - States: New York (Box 18)
      - Taxation
        - General, 3 folders (Box 18)
        - Meetings (Box 18)
        - Alphabetical file, 4 folders (Box 18)
      - Unemployment
        - General (Box 18)
        - Meeting with the President June 14, 1961 (Box 18)
        - Employment and Unemployment Conference April 7, 1961 (Box 18)
      - Vacancy (Box 18)
      - Wayne County Sewer System, 2 folders (Box 18)
      - White House Regional Conference, 2 folders (Box 18)
      - Williams, G. Mennen (Box 18)
      - Youth (Box 18)
    - Federal
      - Federal appointments (Box 19)
      - Cabinet departments
        - Agriculture
          - General (Box 19)
          - Emergency wheat location (Box 19)
        - Army, Secretary of (Box 19)
        - Defense Department (Box 19)
        - Labor Department (Box 19)
        - Treasury Department (Box 19)
      - Other federal agencies
        - Housing (Box 19)
        - International Joint Commission (Box 19)
        - Peace Corps (Box 19)
        - Small Business Administration (Box 19)
      - Legislation
        - Miscellaneous (Box 19)
        - Aging (medical care for) (Box 19)
        - Drugs (HR 3747) (Box 19)
        - Education (federal aid to) (Box 19)
        - Emergency employment (S. 986) (Box 19)
        - Federal Interstate Highway Program (Box 19)
        - Foreign aid (Box 19)
        - Loans and grants for public facilities (Box 19)
        - Minimum wage (Box 19)
        - Nursing homes (HR 4998; S. 1071) (Box 19)
        - Sleeping Bear Dunes, 2 folders (Box 19)
        - Tax exemption-municipal bonds (Box 19)
    - Military Affairs
      - Civil Defense
        - General, 2 folders (Box 19)
        - Walter R. Nunimaker file (Box 19)
        - Advisory Council (Box 19)
        - Shelters (Box 19)
        - Operation Alert (Box 19)
      - Adjutant General (Box 19)
      - Military Board (Box 19)
      - National Guard (Box 19)
      - Naval Militia (Box 19)
    - Veterans Affairs/Selective Service
      - Veterans
        - General (Box 20)
        - Veterans Homestead Tax Exemption (Box 20)
        - Veterans Readjustment Assistance Act (Box 20)
        - Veterans Trust Fund
          - General (Box 20)
          - L.J. LaLone file (Box 20)
      - Selective Service System (Box 20)
    - State Legislature
      - Joint Resolutions (House) (Box 20)
      - House Bills #1-250 (Box 20)
      - House Bills #251-580 (Box 21)
      - House Bills #581-681 (Box 22)
      - Joint Resolutions (Senate) (Box 22)
      - Senate Bills #1001-1215 (Box 22)
      - Senate Bills #1216-1396 (Box 23)
      - Messages of Governor to Legislature (Box 23)
      - Legislation miscellaneous (Box 23)
        (includes communications between governor and legislature; status of legislation; legislative program, etc.)
      - House bill analysis (Box 23)
      - Senate bill analysis (Box 23)
      - Special Session June 15, 1961
        - General (Box 23)
        - Higher education/mental health legislation (Box 23)
      - Press releases
        - Bills signed (Box 23)
        - Bill vetoed (Box 23)
      - Constituent correspondence
        - General [A-Z], 4 folders (Box 23)
        - Numbered files (arranged by bill number)
          - House bills (Box 24)
          - Senate bills (Box 25)
  - 1962 files
    - Boards and Commissions
      - Administrative Board
        - General (Box 25)
        - Meeting files January-May 1962, 10 folders (Box 25)
        - Meeting files June-December 1961, 14 folders (Box 26)
        - Reports, 11 folders (Box 26)
      - Accident Fund Board (Box 26)
      - Accountancy Board (Box 26)
      - Administration, Department of
        - General (Box 26)
        - Planning Administration (Box 26)
      - Aeronautics (Box 26)
      - Aging Commission
        - General (Box 26)
        - Housing (Box 26)
      - Agriculture
        - General (Box 27)
        - G. McIntyre file (Box 27)
        - Administrative Board reports (Box 27)
        - Agriculture Commission meeting, January 22 meeting (Box 27)
        - Japanese beetle (Box 27)
      - Alcoholism Commission (Box 27)
      - Athletic Board of Control (Box 27)
      - Attorney General
        - General (Box 27)
        - Frank Kelley file (Box 27)
      - Auditor General
        - Billy Farnum file (Box 27)
      - Banking Department (Box 27)
      - Barbers, Board of Examiners of (Box 27)
      - Bridge Commission (Box 27)
      - Chiropody, Board of Registration in (Box 27)
      - Civil Service Commission
        - General (Box 27)
        - Frank DeWald, Director, file (Box 27)
      - Civil War Centennial Commission
        - General (Box 27)
        - American Negro Emancipation Centennial (Box 27)
      - Colleges and Universities
        - Central Michigan University (Box 27)
        - Eastern Michigan University (Box 27)
        - Ferris Institute (Box 27)
        - Grand Valley College (Box 27)
        - Michigan College of Mining and Technology
          - General (Box 27)
          - Sault St. Marie branch fire (Box 27)
        - Michigan State University (Box 27)
        - Northern Michigan University (Box 27)
        - University of Michigan
          - General (Box 27)
          - Institute of Science and Technology (Box 27)
        - Wayne State University (Box 27)
        - Western Michigan University (Box 27)
      - Conservation
        - Gerald E. Eddy file (Box 27)
        - Administrative Board reports (Box 27)
        - General (Box 27)
        - Bounty payments (Box 27)
        - Deer (Box 27)
        - Fisheries (Box 27)
        - Interstate Oil Compact Commission (Box 27)
        - Recreation (Box 28)
      - Corporation and Securities Commission (Box 28)
      - Corrections
        - Gus Harrison file (Box 28)
        - General (Box 28)
      - Cosmetology Board (Box 28)
      - Crippled Children Commission (Box 28)
      - Dentistry Board (Box 28)
      - Economic Development Commission
        - General (Box 28)
        - Alphabetical file, 4 folders (Box 28)
        - Industrial Ambassadors (Box 28)
        - Letters to newspapers (Box 28)
        - Michigan Week (Box 28)
        - Research and Industrial Development Committee (Box 28)
      - Education, State Board of
        - General (Box 28)
        - Michigan Rehabilitation Institute (Box 28)
        - School for the Blind (Box 28)
        - School for the Deaf (Box 28)
      - Electrical Administrative Board (Box 28)
      - Employment Security Commission
        - Max Horton file (Box 28)
        - General (Box 28)
        - Carroll Little file (discrimination case) (Box 29)
      - Employment Security Appeal Board (Box 29)
      - Equalization, State Board (Box 29)
      - Escheats, State Board of (Box 29)
      - Fair Commission, Michigan State (Box 29)
      - Fair Employment Practices Commission
        - General (Box 29)
        - Code of Fair Practices, 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Great Lakes Commission (Box 29)
      - Health Department
        - Albert Heustis file (Box 29)
        - General (Box 29)
        - Cancer research (Box 29)
        - Discrimination-Hospitals (Box 29)
        - Mason County Hospital (Box 29)
        - Monroe County Hospitals, 4 folders (Box 29)
      - Higher Education Assistance Authority (Box 29)
      - Highway Department
        - Alphabetical file, 4 folders (Box 29)
        - John C. Mackie file (Box 30)
        - Administrative Board reports (Box 30)
      - Highway Reciprocity Board (Box 30)
      - Historical Commission (Box 30)
      - Insurance Department
        - General (Box 30)
        - Sherwood Colburn file (Box 30)
        - Blue Cross controversy (Box 30)
      - International Bridge Authority of Michigan (Box 30)
      - Interstate Cooperation, Commission on (Box 30)
      - Labor Department
        - General (Box 30)
        - Saginaw school disaster (Box 30)
      - Labor Mediation Board
        - General (Box 30)
        - Bloomfield Hospital (Box 30)
        - Evans Products Company (Box 30)
        - Mt. Carmel Mercy Hospital, 2 folders (Box 30)
        - St. Joseph Hospital (Box 30)
        - St. Mary's Hospital (Box 30)
        - Sparrow Hospital (Box 30)
      - Libraries, State Board of
        - General (Box 30)
        - Governor's Conference on Libraries September 19, 1962 (Box 30)
      - Lieutenant Governor (Box 30)
      - Liquor Control Commission
        - Joseph Wisniewski file (Box 30)
        - Alphabetical file, 4 folders (Box 30)
        - Disposable bottles, 4 folders (Box 31)
      - Mackinac Bridge Authority (Box 31)
      - Mackinac Island Park Commission (Box 31)
      - Medicine, State Board of Registration in (Box 31)
      - Mental Health Department
        - Charles Wagg file (Box 31)
        - Alphabetical file, 4 folders (Box 31)
        - Geriatrics program (Camp Lucas) (Box 31)
        - Plymouth State Home and Training School (Box 31)
      - Mortuary Science Board (Box 31)
      - Municipal Finance Commission (Box 31)
      - Nursing, Michigan Board of (Box 31)
      - Optometry, State Board of Examiners in (Box 31)
      - Osteopathic Registration and Examination, Board of (Box 31)
      - Pharmacy
        - General (Box 31)
        - Dangerous drugs (Box 31)
      - Plumbing Board (Box 31)
      - Police, State
        - General (Box 31)
        - Joseph A. Childs file (Box 31)
        - Administrative Board reports (Box 31)
        - Civil Defense transfer (Box 31)
      - Port of Detroit (Box 31)
      - Port of Monroe (Box 31)
      - Potato Industry Council (Box 31)
      - Private Employment Agencies, State Superintendent of (Box 31)
      - Public Instruction
        - General (Box 31)
        - Lynn Bartlett file (Box 31)
        - President's Youth Fitness Council (Box 31)
        - Vocational Education and Rehabilitation Division (Box 31)
      - Public Service Commission
        - General (Box 31)
        - James Inglis file (Box 31)
        - Consumer's Power Company (Box 32)
        - Michigan Bell Telephone Company (Box 32)
        - Monroe, Michigan (re rates for gas service in the city) (Box 32)
        - Upper Peninsula Gas (Box 32)
      - Racing Commission
        - General (Box 32)
        - Administrative Board reports (Box 32)
        - Berrien County (proposed race track) (Box 32)
      - Retirement boards
        - Judges Retirement Board (Box 32)
        - Municipal Employees Retirement Board (Box 32)
        - Public School Employees Retirement Board (Box 32)
        - Probate Judges Retirement System (Box 32)
        - State Employees Retirement Board (Box 32)
      - Revenue Department (Box 32)
      - Safety Commission
        - General (Box 32)
        - Gerald Shipman file (Box 32)
      - Secretary of State (Box 32)
      - Ski Area Safety Board (Box 32)
      - Social Welfare Commission
        - General (Box 32)
        - W.J. Maxey file (Box 32)
        - Proposed study committee (Box 32)
        - ADC
          - Suitable housing (Box 32)
          - Unemployed (Box 32)
        - Boys Vocational School (Box 32)
        - Food Stamp program (Box 32)
        - Girls Training School (Box 32)
        - Scholarship-State Wards (Box 32)
      - Soil Conservation Committee (Box 32)
      - Supreme Court (Box 32)
      - Tax Appeals, Board of (Box 32)
      - Tax Commission (Box 32)
      - Tenure Commission (Box 32)
      - Tourist Council (Box 32)
      - Treasurer, State (Box 32)
      - Veterans Facility, Michigan (Box 32)
      - Water Resources Commission
        - General (Box 33)
        - Milton Adams file (Box 33)
        - Detroit River pollution (Box 33)
        - Federal Legislation Planning Act (Box 33)
      - Waterways Commission
        - General (Box 33)
        - Keith Wilson file (Box 33)
        - Trenton Channel (Box 33)
      - Workmen's Compensation Commission (Box 33)
      - Workmen's Compensation Appeal Board (Box 33)
    - General Subjects
      - Appointments (Box 33)
      - Area Redevelopment
        - General (Box 33)
        - Letters (Box 33)
        - Rural Area Redevelopment (Box 33)
      - Certificates-Citations (Box 33)
      - Civil Rights
        - General (Box 33)
        - Meeting of Fair Employment Practices Commission and the Michigan Employment Security Commission January 8, 1962 (Box 33)
        - Admission of James Meredith to the University of Mississippi, 2 folders (Box 33)
      - Communism (Box 33)
      - Conferences
        - General (Box 33)
        - Economic Development (Box 33)
        - National Tax Association (Box 33)
        - Rivers and Harbors Congress (Box 33)
      - Constitutional Convention, 6 folders (Box 34)
      - Council of State Governments (Box 34)
      - Counties
        - Gogebic (Box 34)
      - Detroit, City of (Box 34)
      - Disaster relief (Box 34)
      - Distressed Areas (Box 34)
      - Education
        - General, 2 folders (Box 34)
        - Educational TV, 2 folders (Box 34)
        - Higher Education (Box 34)
      - Elections (Box 34)
      - Emergency Interim Successors (Box 34)
      - Food for Peace (Box 34)
      - Friend of the Court (Box 34)
      - Greater Michigan Foundation (Box 34)
      - Group Visitors (Tunisian Women's Group) (Box 34)
      - Governor's Conference (Midwestern Conference), December (Box 34)
      - Housing (Box 34)
      - Inter-Agency Council for Recreation (Box 34)
      - Invitations-Outgoing (Box 34)
      - Judgeships (Box 34)
      - Jury Commission (Box 34)
      - Juvenile Delinquency (Box 34)
      - Lake Michigan Region Planning Committee (Box 34)
      - Legal Holidays (Box 34)
      - Library cards (Box 34)
      - Local government (Box 34)
      - Metropolitan area problems (Box 34)
      - Migrant labor (Box 34)
      - Mississippi-Admission of James Meredith to the University of Mississippi, 3 folders (Box 34)
      - Mississippi-Admission of James Meredith to the University of Mississippi, 2 folders (Box 35)
      - Nationalities-Polish meeting May 14, 1962 (Box 35)
      - Notary publics 1961-1962 (Box 35)
      - People to People program (Box 35)
      - Port developments (Box 35)
      - Prayer Room and Prayer Breakfasts 1961-1962 (Box 35)
      - Radio-TV
        - General (Box 35)
        - Swainson-Romney debate (Box 35)
      - Resolutions (Box 35)
      - Savings Bonds (Box 35)
      - Sewers-Drains (Box 35)
      - Taxation
        - General, 4 folders (Box 35)
        - Detroit Income Tax (Box 35)
        - Michigan Income Tax, 5 folders (Box 35)
        - Nuisances Taxes (Box 36)
        - Property Taxes (Box 36)
      - Transportation (Box 36)
      - Unemployment (Box 36)
      - Unions (Box 36)
      - United Nations (Box 36)
      - Vacancy (Box 36)
      - Veterans Day (Box 36)
      - Wayne County Sewer System (Box 36)
      - Wolverine Boys State (Box 36)
      - World's Fair 1961-1962, 2 folders (Box 36)
      - Young American Medals 1961-1962, 2 folders (Box 36)
      - Youth Commission
        - CCC camps (Box 36)
        - Employment opportunities (Box 36)
    - Federal
      - Miscellaneous (Box 36)
      - Executive: U.S. President (Box 36)
      - Executive: U.S. Vice President (Box 36)
      - Executive: Cabinet departments
        - Agriculture (Box 36)
        - Air Force (Box 36)
        - Army, Secretary of (Box 36)
        - Attorney General (Box 36)
        - Commerce Department
          - General (Box 36)
          - National Defense Executive Reserve (Box 36)
        - Defense Department
          - General (Box 36)
          - Defense Contract Information Center (Box 36)
        - Health, Education and Welfare Department (Box 36)
        - Interior Department (Box 36)
        - Labor Department (Box 36)
        - Postmaster General (Box 36)
        - Secretary of State (Box 36)
      - Executive: Other federal agencies
        - Budget, Bureau of the (Box 36)
        - Communications (Box 36)
        - Housing, 2 folders (Box 36)
        - Intergovernmental Relations (Box 36)
        - Internal Revenue Department (Box 36)
        - International Joint Commission (Box 36)
        - Peace Corps (Box 37)
        - Small Business Administration (Box 37)
      - Legislative
        - U.S. Congress: General (Box 37)
        - U.S. Senate: General (Box 37)
        - U.S. Senate: Philip A. Hart (Box 37)
        - U.S. Senate: Patrick McNamara (Box 37)
      - Legislation
        - Miscellaneous (Box 37)
        - Aged, Medical Care for the (Box 37)
        - Aging Commission (Box 37)
        - Reciprocal Trade (Box 37)
        - Sleeping Bear Dunes (Box 37)
        - Standby Capital Improvement Act/Accelerated Public Works Program, 3 folders (Box 37)
    - Military Affairs
      - Civil Defense
        - R.S. D'Amelio, Acting Director, file, 3 folders (Box 37)
        - General, 2 folders (Box 37)
        - Advisory Council (Box 37)
        - Civil Defense Long-Term Advisory Committee (Box 37)
        - Shelters (Box 37)
        - Manuals, reports, and other published source materials (Box 38)
      - Adjutant General
        - General (Box 39)
        - Ronald McDonald file (Box 39)
        - Administrative Board reports (Box 39)
      - National Guard
        - C.L. Simmons, Commander (Box 39)
        - General (Box 39)
        - Reduction/Reorganization (Box 39)
        - Michigan State Troops 1961-1962 (Box 39)
      - Naval Militia (Box 39)
    - Veterans Affairs/Selective Service
      - Veterans
        - General (Box 39)
        - Veterans Trust Fund Board
          - L.J. LaLone file (Box 39)
          - Alphabetical file, 4 folders (Box 39)
      - Selective Service System (Box 39)
    - State Legislature
      - Joint Resolutions (House) (Box 39)
      - House Bills #1-115 (Box 39)
      - House Bills #116-495 (Box 40)
      - House Bills #496-782 (Box 41)
      - Joint Resolutions (Senate) (Box 41)
      - Senate Bills #1001-1047 (Box 41)
      - Senate Bills #1048-1385 (Box 42)
      - Senate Bills #1386-1456 (Box 43)
      - Messages of Governor to Legislature (Box 43)
        (includes exaugural address, January 9, 1963)
      - Veto Messages (Box 43)
      - Legislation miscellaneous (Box 43)
        (includes communications between governor and legislature; status of legislation; etc.)
      - Legislative Program 1962 (Box 43)
      - Press releases (Box 43)
      - Constituent correspondence
        - General [A-Z], 4 folders (Box 43)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 43)
        - Numbered files (arranged by bill number)
          - House bills (Box 43)
          - House bills (cont.) (Box 44)
          - House bills (cont.) (Box 45)
          - Senate bills (Box 45)
  - Press Office
    - 1961
      - Speeches (reading copy) January-November 1961 (Box 46)
      - Speeches (reading copy) December 1961 (Box 47)
      - Speeches (mimeographed copy), 1961, 2 folders (Box 47)
      - Schedules (Box 47)
      - Invitations regrets (monthly lists) (Box 47)
      - Press releases
        - Monthly file, 12 folders (Box 47)
        - Bills signed, 2 folders (Box 47)
        - Bills vetoes (Box 47)
        - Bills without signature (Box 47)
        - Appointments (Box 47)
        - Proclamations (Box 47)
      - Governor's Column October-December 1961, 2 folders (Box 48)
    - 1962
      - Speeches (reading copy) January-December 1962 (Box 48)
      - Speeches (mimeographed copy) 1962, 4 folders (Box 49)
      - Notes used in press conferences (Box 49)
      - Schedules, 6 folders (Box 49)
      - Invitations regrets (monthly lists) (Box 49)
      - Record of governor's visits to counties 1961-1962 (Box 49)
      - Press releases
        - Chronological file, 7 folders (Box 49)
        - Bills signed (Box 49)
        - Bills vetoed (Box 49)
        - Bills without signature (Box 49)
        - Appointments (Box 49)
        - Proclamations (Box 49)
      - Governor's Column January-November 1962, 7 folders (Box 49)
    - Various
      - Scrapbook January 1961-February 1962 (Volume 1)
        (located in AC)
        (Clippings located throughout the collection; packets of unmounted press service clippings have not been retained; the researcher is directed to the index of the Detroit News Lansing Bureau scrapbook collection for coverage of Swainson's tenure as governor)
      - Clippings 1962 (Box 49)
      - Clippings (Alice Swainson) (Box 49)
    - Sound Recordings
      - January 1, 1961 Inauguration ceremonies of JBS, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes; 7 in. (Box 50)
      - May 1961 JBS appearing on American Bandstand program upon occasion of Michigan Week, May 21-27, 1961, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes; ? ips; 7 in. (Box 50)